Don't
Speaker 1: worry, we'll have time at the end if you're still signing up. We'll have time at the end.
Alright, well this
Speaker 1: next speaker doesn't need much of an intro because he helped open the show with me, but I just want to stress again the importance of talking about men, the importance
of...
Speaker 1: responding to the rise of radical feminism. 'Cause it is radical and it's angry. And everything that they're advocating for directly impacts our communities. I find that I get a lot of bad slack in the press, especially it's been hard for me to connect with a certain audience. But Brandon Tatum has a way of speaking like a father and people really respond to him.
And
Speaker 1: fatherhood and father absence, in my opinion, is the number one issue that is facing not just the black community, but all communities, all communities. We need men. We need fathers. So without further ado, please welcome to the stage. Give a big welcome to Brandon Tatum.
what's going
Speaker 3: on
Speaker 4: all right I'm gonna jump right into
Speaker 5 (higher-pitched voice): this thing real quick it is invaluable for us to understand our position as men
I want
Speaker 5 (higher-pitched voice): to talk to the men right now I want to employ power
Speaker 6 (higher-pitched voice): into the men of this country let me tell you this
Our
Speaker 6 (higher-pitched voice): forefathers fought, was beat and bruised for us to live in a great country like we do today.
And we live in a
Speaker 6 (higher-pitched voice): great country, we need to start taking
Woman 7: responsibility for our position as black American men.
We always talk about
Woman 7: fatherless
Speaker 8 (higher-pitched voice): homes. We always talk about the stats. We were at 22% way back in the 60s and now we're at 70%.
Speaker 8 (higher-pitched voice): I'm going to go on a limb and say that the responsibility of fathers being in a home is with the men.
If you
Speaker 6 (higher-pitched voice): have enough courage, if you have enough, whatever you want to call it, to lay down,
then you
Speaker 6 (higher-pitched voice): need to have enough to stay and take care of your doggone children.
And I know it feel like
Speaker 6 (higher-pitched voice): chastisement, but I feel like that the only way
Speaker 6 (higher-pitched voice): That we're going to actually see a revolution. We're going to actually see us get back to what we should be in this country is if we start with the responsibility of the man. I don't want to hear no more excuses. I don't want to hear nothing about the crack cocaine epidemic. Listen, if you love your brothers and sisters like you say you do, there's not an amount of money in the world that can get you to give a drug to your brother.
Speaker 6 (higher-pitched voice): There's not amount of money in the world for you to pick up a gun and shoot your brother
That is a
Speaker 6 (higher-pitched voice): responsibility as held by us We have to stand strong in that principle I'm
sick of
Speaker 6 (higher-pitched voice): us hearing about our people talking about oh when I go to a job They're gonna discriminate against me man. What about white privilege? I
Speaker 8 (higher-pitched voice): don't want to hear a lick of that crap anymore
You're stronger
Speaker 8 (higher-pitched voice): than that You're more powerful than that
Speaker 8 (higher-pitched voice): I'll tell you what, I go to a job interview and someone don't give me an opportunity. I'm going to apply for every single job on a block until I get a job. I don't need no handouts. I don't need your excuses. I'm going to go harder than everybody else for that job.
And if you go
Speaker 8 (higher-pitched voice): hard and you put yourself in position, you will be successful. I don't want to hear no more rhetoric about making excuses for young
Speaker 6 (higher-pitched voice): brothers walking around with their pants sagging.
no
Speaker 6 (higher-pitched voice): more excuses pull your doggone pants up and become
a man Martin Luther King
Woman 7: wasn't walking around with his pants hanging down Martin Luther King stood up as an example he stood up as a strong man he fought for what he was fighting for until
his death and
Woman 7: we have become so
Speaker 6 (higher-pitched voice): cowardice and we allowed them to demasculate or emasculate men in this
country
listen
Speaker 6 (higher-pitched voice): God has
Speaker 8 (higher-pitched voice): already told us and given us the recipe for success Jesus is the head of
Speaker 6 (higher-pitched voice): the church the man is the
head of the household we wonder
Speaker 6 (higher-pitched voice): why in our culture and our society that we see so many problems and it's not the women's fault right women are go been going hard for I don't know how many years women are up at the church on every Sunday praying
We need
Speaker 6 (higher-pitched voice): to get our butts at the church and
Woman 7: start praying. We need to be the first ones in the church and the last ones to leave. We need to be leading the sermons. We
need to be going
Woman 7: out into the communities.
Speaker 6 (higher-pitched voice): I cannot stress it enough how invaluable my father was. Now, I love my mama. If it wasn't for my mama, I probably wouldn't have the character that I do today because she should tell me, baby, tell the truth. Say how you feel. And mama got me to that point of feeling comfortable in my skin, but it took my father forever.
Speaker 6 (higher-pitched voice): To not just be a verbal representation of what a man should be, but a physical reputation of what a man should be. A representation of what a man should be. My father was strong. My father didn't take no
mess. My
Speaker 6 (higher-pitched voice): dad didn't want to hear no excuses. You tell me you late to school, then you should have left earlier. You got a flat tire, well you should have brought a spare. You got two, you should have left early enough to bring two spares and walk to school on time.
That's what a
Speaker 6 (higher-pitched voice): real man does.
My
Speaker 6 (higher-pitched voice): daddy don't waste his time talking. He don't talk a lot. He's all about action. My daddy started on the fire department here in Fort Worth, Texas. Started on the fire department when he was 18 years old. He
talked to me
Speaker 6 (higher-pitched voice): about that there was discrimination that would go on on the fire department. And you know what his mentality was? It wasn't a victim mentality. Oh man, the white man, they not going to give me opportunities. My dad said, you know what, you'll be
Speaker 9: working for me one day. So you better watch the way you treat me.
And you know
Speaker 9: what?
They
Speaker 9: were working for my dad because he made all the way to the top.
Retired as a
Speaker 8 (higher-pitched voice): battalion chief. And now he is the chief of the Waco Fire Department as we speak.
But you know, my dad didn't have his
Speaker 8 (higher-pitched voice): father
Speaker 6 (higher-pitched voice): around. He didn't have his dad. My grandfather left a long time ago. And what hurts my heart is the fact that people don't understand the residual effect when fathers aren't there.
They
Speaker 6 (higher-pitched voice): don't understand the residual effects when people go to prison. I remember my family, we used to have family gatherings, family dinners
Woman 7: all the time. And then people started going to jail and now we don't even meet. Now everybody's moved
Speaker 6 (higher-pitched voice): away.
How does a
Speaker 6 (higher-pitched voice): young man, see
my dad
Speaker 6 (higher-pitched voice): did a great job at this, but how does a young man learn how to be a father when he don't have an example at
home?
And
Speaker 6 (higher-pitched voice): what happens is, and I know Candace talks about this a lot, what happens is young men are seeking love and appreciation and support from another man. It's
not a
Speaker 6 (higher-pitched voice): matter of sexuality, it's a matter of a necessity from a human being. God has conditioned us to need and support or need the support of another man. I don't speak of the men. And
when you see
Speaker 6 (higher-pitched voice): young brothers without their fathers, they find and attach themselves to other men.
The
Speaker 6 (higher-pitched voice): problem that I'm seeing in our society and in our culture is that we're attaching ourselves to the wrong types of men. We're attaching ourselves to dudes in the hood because, to be honest, in some cases, the dudes in the hood are the only ones that show you some love. The dudes in the hood are the only ones that got your back. Because mama can only be so strong, but she can't fight for you. She's not gonna go blow the blow with people. So we attach ourselves to the wrong types of leaders in our community. Then we see the leaders that's on TV every
day
Speaker 6 (higher-pitched voice): They're fake, they're phony, they're fraudulent. They don't care, they're opportunists. They don't care about the black community. I remember when we had 400 black conservative leaders from all over the country go down to the White House and everybody was passionate. I ain't never seen so many black people wearing mega hats
in my
Speaker 6 (higher-pitched voice): life. But everybody went down to the White House. They treated us with respect and dignity. Everybody was proud. We marched from a hotel to the White House.
It was
Speaker 6 (higher-pitched voice): one of the proudest moments I ever had in my life.
And then
Speaker 6 (higher-pitched voice): what do they do? They put another black man, Al Sharpton, on the television to tell the world that we have been paid to wear those hats, that we have been paid to go to the White House. And that's a doggone shame. Those people
Speaker 5 (higher-pitched voice): need to be called out every single chance we get.
I'm not here to
Speaker 6 (higher-pitched voice): be a Debbie Downer, but I want to implement power to you. I want to extend power to the young men in this room. Because you need to go out and be an example to other young brothers. Because you are the leaders of your community, believe it or not. Some of these other young brothers are hurt. They still haven't been able to overcome the brainwashing. But you have been delivered.
And I
Speaker 6 (higher-pitched voice): believe that this is not only a natural experience, but this is a godly experience. This is a spiritual experience. Two things that have happened to me that has revolutionized my life. One was when I got saved, baptized in Jesus' name, and I got filled with the Holy Spirit.
And the second thing is I woke up to the
Speaker 6 (higher-pitched voice): reality that
Woman 7: I'm actually a conservative. I'm
not a
Woman 7: victim.
Nobody's
Woman 7: gonna hold me back or tell me nothing. I'm a grown man with responsibilities. When
I woke up
Woman 7: to that fact, I became more successful. I became more loving. I became more dedicated to patriotism
Speaker 6 (higher-pitched voice): in my community. Most of y'all know I was a police officer. That was one of the greatest decisions that I ever made in my life. The first
Speaker 10: time in my life I saw a hero when I
did a ride-along.
That
Speaker 10: inspired me to see a man go from changing a flat tire to saving a kid's life.
Going 80
Speaker 6 (higher-pitched voice): miles per hour down the road. No thanks at all. A thankless job. I remember going out and I have a young son. I remember thinking to myself that I'm willing to risk everything
for my
Speaker 6 (higher-pitched voice): community. My dreams, my goals, my future with my child. I'm willing to risk it all to protect and serve my community.
Right?
And
Speaker 6 (higher-pitched voice): we really, young men, I'm talking to y'all. And young ladies, tell your boyfriend when you get home or your husband or whatever. Y'all can tell him, show him this video
Speaker 8 (higher-pitched voice): later.
But we
Speaker 8 (higher-pitched voice): need to get back, and I'm not going to say too much about it, but we need to get back to understanding our position in serving.
Speaker 6 (higher-pitched voice): We want people to serve us. We want to sit around and say, what can the country do for me? Instead of saying, what can I do for this country? What
can I
Speaker 6 (higher-pitched voice): do for my community? And that's something that's very...
It
Speaker 6 (higher-pitched voice): holds dear to me in my heart that I want us to get back to that. I want us to be strong again. I want us to stand up and be leaders in our communities. I want people to
Speaker 11: come and look to us for advice and guidance. Young brothers, you are the ones.
You are
Speaker 11: the ones. You are the chosen ones.
And we need to continue to be bold
Speaker 10: and stand
Speaker 6 (higher-pitched voice): up.
Speaker 6 (higher-pitched voice): I know it's hard. See, I live a I live sort of a cush life when it comes to exposing the fact that I support the president and all
Speaker 5 (higher-pitched voice): those things. I
live in
Speaker 5 (higher-pitched voice): a community that's a real community. I live in a community where I don't have to deal with a lot of drama if I don't want to. Online don't mean nothing to me. All right. That's
Speaker 12: that's a bunch of talking. And
I tell you
Speaker 12: what, ain't nobody going to try me in person. I just want to. I
just want
Speaker 12: to be honest with y'all for a minute. But
but you've
Speaker 12: got to be strong
Speaker 5 (higher-pitched voice): because people are looking to you.
To
Speaker 5 (higher-pitched voice): be that example, I wear my Trump hat everywhere I go, I stopped wearing it lately because it don't match my outfit that good. But everywhere I go, I wear my hat,
Speaker 6 (higher-pitched voice): and it's not to trigger people and all this stuff, it's to let people know that I'm strong in my convictions. And I'm going to stand for what I believe no matter what. And I always tell people, do you think that Martin Luther King really felt like going through all
that drama?
Woman 7: That man was a man of God.
He
Woman 7: had a lot of influence. He had a great family. I think he could have had a legacy, whether or not he stood up in front of
Speaker 5 (higher-pitched voice): the world or not. He was a great man, but he understood that it was his position to do something that's greater than himself.
It was his
Speaker 5 (higher-pitched voice): position to lead the world
Speaker 6 (higher-pitched voice): like God wanted him to. I use that same idea when I talk about the president. I talk about President Trump.
Do you
Speaker 6 (higher-pitched voice): think a billionaire...
Want
Speaker 8 (higher-pitched voice): to put his millions of billions aside to come and be ridiculed and lied on for no reason?
Do you think he
Woman 7: really wanted to do that? He probably didn't. He could be living a cush life, doing this thing,
but he
Woman 7: said I'm
Speaker 5 (higher-pitched voice): going to do something that's greater than myself because I understand that what I'm going to do now, the sacrifices that I make now, are going to help generations to come. And y'all can give that
Speaker 13: a round of applause. And
Speaker 13: And the last person that I love the most,
well, you think
Speaker 13: Jesus wanted to do that?
Look how
Speaker 13: they beat him.
Look how they
Speaker 13: beat him up.
Look how
Speaker 13: they lied on
Speaker 6 (higher-pitched voice): him.
I'm not
Speaker 6 (higher-pitched voice): trying to compare Jesus to Trump, but I'm saying that haters are going to do the same thing no matter who you are. When they go to judge him, they lie.
They come
Speaker 6 (higher-pitched voice): up with
Woman 7: stories. They have nothing against this man,
but they're
Woman 7: afraid of that man.
Woman 7: because he stood up and he was strong he stood up on principles no matter what they thought of him
he stood
Woman 7: up and he taught young people
and he
Speaker 8 (higher-pitched voice): labored he could have been a god i'm saying in a sense of walking and being popular and
Speaker 6 (higher-pitched voice): having all the money in the world but he didn't he put that aside to humble himself that's what we need to do humble yourself
and jesus knowing that he
Speaker 5 (higher-pitched voice): would die at the end of it he still did
it
He
Speaker 5 (higher-pitched voice): still made that sacrifice and
I think that
Speaker 5 (higher-pitched voice): we need to do the same thing today young brothers
They may
Speaker 9: talk about you. They may talk trash on you. They may want to put their hands on you
But you got to
Speaker 8 (higher-pitched voice): understand that if you don't stand up now if
you don't put
Speaker 8 (higher-pitched voice): your best foot for it right now We're gonna lose our community We're gonna lose
Speaker 5 (higher-pitched voice): our community
and I'm
Speaker 5 (higher-pitched voice): not gonna put it on the backs of the women. I'm not I
And
Speaker 5 (higher-pitched voice): I'm not saying that they're not capable. I
had a
Speaker 5 (higher-pitched voice): great mom. She would actually fight people on my behalf. Literally. I've seen it.
Let me tie my
Speaker 5 (higher-pitched voice): shoe. I've seen it.
But what
Speaker 5 (higher-pitched voice): I'm saying is that we need to put... We need to understand our position and
Speaker 12: we need to stand strong.
And the
Speaker 12: reason I said that, and I think I repeated it three times, because when you say things three times, people begin to get it in their mind. I want the repetition to stick with you. If you don't remember nothing else, I say. You don't remember me tying my shoe and none of that stuff. I want you to remember...
Speaker 12: that it is your time and i'll finish with this i say this everywhere i go i
tell the story about
Speaker 10: wolverine right i'm gonna do it real quick you know wolverine he pull out the spikes and he's just a bad mamma jamma right he whooping butt everywhere he go he whooping everybody
Woman 7: but but at the beginning it seems like he's getting his butt kicked right you're like come on wolverine get up you're supposed to be the hero they whooping your butt
he
Woman 7: ain't healing right and all this other stuff but it seems like he recovers and then when he recover he whoop everybody like he ain't never started fighting and then you're like dang you know i always think that Wolverine will lose you know but he always seems to win and then when i look at when i look at the situation for what it is i say you know what they already wrote in the script before he started that he was going to win
in the end
Woman 7: and i honestly believe as sure as i'm standing on this stage
Woman 7: That God has already written
Speaker 6 (higher-pitched voice): in the script that when you start, he's already written out your success in the end.
Beyond the doubt. Beyond the doubt of insecurity. You
Woman 7: know that when you go out and you employ the things that I told you, that in the end of everything, you will win.